

## **Julien Cresus**

### **UX** Designer

### **About Me**

Paris-born & London-based. I use my skills to create meaningful and user-centred experiences through empathy and problem-solving.
When I'm not designing, you

can catch me getting tackled on a **rugby pitch** or in the **kitchen** baking. Also, never missed a PlayStation launch since 2000.

### **Skillset**

### Tools

Adobe Suite • Figma • Sketch • inVision Studio • Miro

### Languages

HTML/CSS • Javascript • jQuery • React • Frameworks (Bootstrap...)

## Methods

UX/UI Design
Wireframing
Prototyping
Design systems
User research
Personas
Journey maps
Remote testing
Agile methodology

### **Contact**

julcresus.github.io cresusjulien@gmail.com

+44 7983 804889

# **Experience**

## Senior User Experience Designer @ Dam Digital

April 2022 - now, London, UK

- Work on projects in the private sector, such as charities and private aviation
- Build prototpyes and user journeys, using Miro and Figma
- Follow projects through the whole design process and collaborate in agile teams with developers, UI, and project managers, using JIRA and Confluence

### **UX Designer @ Methods**

Feb 2019 - April 2022, London, UK

- Work on projects with governement-led clients such as Every Mind Matters for Public Health England, the National Funding Formula for the Education and Skills Funding Agency and other projects for Ministry of Defense
- Build user journeys, personas and other design artefacts based on user research
- Design and develop GDS-approved prototypes using Figma and the Government Design System online toolkit
- Help user research by assisting on user testing and workshops with the stakeholders, using Teams and Miro
- Collaborate with developers to understand the technical requirements and be a link between both developers and research, using JIRA and Trello

### UX / UI Designer Trainee @ Societe Generale Design

Sept 2017 - Dec 2018, London, UK

- Work on projects from financially-led (ex. trading platform) to company social (ex. internal project incubator)
- Coordinate co-creation workshops with Product Owners, End Users and IT teams
- Create iterative high-fidelity and low-fidelity prototypes on Adobe XD and Sketch

## **Education**

### **User Experience Design MSc**

2018, London, UK

#### Thesis:

Concept creation and prototyping development of an autism awareness virtual reality app based on WebVR and storytelling

### Fields of study:

- Usability evaluation: UX testing, feedback analysis, wireframing
- User research: data gathering, personas, user needs, user journeys & scenarios
- Design research: guidelines, touchpoints, prototyping

## Web Design Bachelor

2016, Paris, France

#### Fields of study:

- User Interface & Experience
- Web Development (HTML/CSS)
- Project Management